<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Gianluca Aguzzi</title><link>https://cric96.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Gianluca Aguzzi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Copyright notice</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 22:06:44 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cric96.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why a personal website?</title><link>https://cric96.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 22:06:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://cric96.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid><description>In a social network era, what the hell bring me to build a personal website? So, mainly I choose to do so for:
having my place in which post my research/activity in a non-standard format studying modern technologies for building static website (like Hugo, Actions) Enjoying :) I am not a verbose guy, so I don&amp;rsquo;t have as much to say about my decision. For apologizing, I drop here a kitten.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://cric96.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cric96.github.io/about/</guid><description>I love computer science because it allows me to shape my ideas in a short time. I&amp;rsquo;m just lazy enough to be able to get away from work.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always been fascinated by technology because everything seemed like magic to me as a child. Understanding its dynamics has also made everything more magical and fascinating.
My current interests concern machine learning algorithms, functional languages, design patterns, architectural patterns, and mixing AI techniques with standard programming techniques.</description></item><item><title>My Research Interest</title><link>https://cric96.github.io/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cric96.github.io/research/</guid><description>My current research topics concern large-scale system coordination and machine learning algorithm in distributed systems. In my research group, we study a technique called Aggregate Computing, a top-down declarative approach to coordinate collective behaviour. Over the years, my colleagues developed novel tool-chain to use this new paradigm, such as ScaFi and Protelis.
My current trend consists in merging Aggregate Computing with Machine learning, gaining benefits of both worlds.
I am also the creator of ScaFi-Web, a web-based tool to use Aggregate Computing directly on the web.</description></item></channel></rss>